-《越狱》前情提要K -让我搞清楚一点
- Previously on Prison Break: - Let me get this straight.
这对兄弟回到越狱监狱外 15里的城市，为什么？
Brothers come to a city that's 15 miles from the prison they escaped from. Why?
也许因为总统要在芝加哥演说 他们另有计谋
The president's in Chicago to make a speech, they're up to something.
在法律上来说 这段录音毫无用处
Legally speaking, this tape is useless.
-所以我们要勒索她 -换取什么？
- So we blackmail her. - In exchange for what?
总统大赦
A presidential pardon.
赏金已经是你的了 你想继续吵着要钱
We gonna keep crying about money you've got coming to you?
-还是想多赚一点？ -你说吧
- Or do you wanna make some more? - I'm listening.
去过墨西哥吗？
Ever been to Mexico?
餐点什么时候上？ 我快饿死了
When's the meal coming? I'm starved.
有空请帮我倒饮料，亲爱的
Freshen me up when you get a chance.
费南多
Fernando. Fernando.
-我帮你托运行李 -不，我要随身带着
- Check this bag for you, sir. - Oh, no, that's coming with me.
先生，那已经远远超过 随身行李的重量限制
Sir, I know that bag is way over the weight limit for carryon.
你的行李很安全的
Your bag will be safe.
他们在监视你，可是在哪里？ 那里
They're watching you. But from where? There.
雷诺兹总统毁了你们的人生 她也毁了我的人生
President Reynolds ruined your life, she ruined my life.
如果你们想搞垮这贱人
You wanna take the bitch down?
我就是最佳内线 但现在是唯一机会
You found your inside man, but it's gotta be right now.
这两人有来住房吗？
Have either of these men checked in?
有，1006房
Yeah. Room 1006.
之后我会送包裹到你的牢房
Later you'll get a package in your cell. It's from me.
我要你使用它，懂吗？
I need you to use it, okay?
打开四号房
Open on 4.
我需要人手帮忙
I need a hand in here.
-派医护人员到B4 -让我死
- I need a medic in B-4. - Let me die.
不K
No.
-让我死 -不要说话
- Let me die. - Save your breath.
群众已经聚集在 芝加哥市区的沃巴什大道
A large crowd is gathering along Wabash Avenue here in downtown chicago,
他们正期待着 卡洛琳雷诺兹总统的莅临
They're anticipating the arrival of President caroline Reynolds,,,
她竞选活动的一环 便是到卡莱尔大饭店出席活动
...who continues her tour with an appearance at the Grand carlisle Hotel,
内圈快要进入南区，第一区
Inner circle approaching the south perimeter, Mark One,
第二区
Marker Two,
第三区
Marker Three,
好
okay.
我想你最好先离开
I think you better go.
-你确定？ -对
- You sure? - Yeah.
感谢你的帮忙 不过你已经没办法再帮忙了
Thank you for your help. There's nothing more you can do for us.
这样就离开感觉不对
Doesn't feel right.
你不会想介入这淌浑水的，谢谢
I don't think you want any part of this. Thank you.
-在十分钟路程的地方？ -至少
- It's 10 minutes away, right? - At least.
听着，如果行不通 我们需要后路
Listen, this doesn't work, we're gonna need a way out.
-永远消失的退路 -这要靠你了
- For good. - Well, that's on you.
好，德瑞克如何？
Yeah. What about Derek?
-德瑞克史威尼？ -对
- Derek sweeney? - Yeah.
-你认为他肯帮忙？ -对
- You think he'll be up for this? - Yeah.
好吧
All right.
这一带你熟 要在公园会合吗？
This is your neck of the woods. You wanna meet at the park?
-第三街和雷辛街口如何？ -第三街和雷辛街口
- How's Third and Racine? - Third and Racine.
3点15分，我会在街角等
3:15, the corner. I'll be there.
如果发生意外
If anything happens...
我爱你们俩
...I love you both.
钥匙
Key.
快离开
Go, go, go.
坐下
Sit down.
片名：越狱风云
剧名：亲爱的总统女士
他们离开多久了？ 五、十分钟？
When were they here? Five, 10 minutes?
-他们没来过这里 -他们有，我知道
- They were never here. - They were here. I know.
他们去哪里了？
Where did they go?
-我不知道 -不，你一定知道
- I don't know. - No, you do know.
他决定离开我比较好 而且我也无法再忍受了
He decided it was for the best and I couldn't take this anymore.
-就这样结束了？ -对
- It's over, just like that, huh? - Yeah.
就像你上次用死人的证件 坐飞机去新墨西哥见他一样？
It's over like you flew to New Mexico on a dead woman's ID to meet up with him?
像你在伊凡斯维尔 火车站和他见面一样？
Or it's over like when you met up at the train station in Evansville?
或是像今天你两小时前 住进这家饭店一样
Or maybe like the day today, when you checked in this hotel here two hours ago.
-是哪一种情况？ -我不在乎你相不相信我
- Which one? - I don't care if you believe me or not.
-我说的是实话 -他不打算打电话给你吗？
- I'm telling you the truth. - No call. He's not gonna call you?
别想骗我，你不会想的
Don't lie to me. You don't wanna do that.
（墨西哥墨西哥市 国际机场）
不好意思，请问你知道K？
Excuse me, can you tell me where to find?
喂，老兄
Hey. Hey, hombre.
等等
Hey.
我需要打电话
Hey, I need the phone,
听我说，我今天一定要打电话
Listen to me, man. It needs to be today.
我的家人有麻烦 有一个人
My family is in trouble, all right? There's a man out there...
-会伤害我的家人 -你家人很好
...trying to hurt my... - Your family's fine.
-没有人会伤害你的家人 -你看着我
- There's nobody after your family. - Look at me, man.
我没有发疯，知道吗？
Look, I'm not crazy, okay?
我懂得规矩
I know the rules.
如果不是紧急事件 我不会求你
I wouldn't be asking you if it wasn't an emergency.
拜托，让我打电话
Please, just let me use that phone.
求求你
Please.
（伊利诺州芝加哥 调查局分局）
-我是兰恩探员 -是K
- Agent Lang. - Yeah, yeah,
我K要找曼宏
l... I need to speak to Mahone, please,
-请他回电可以吗？ -我是班哲明迈尔斯富兰克林
- Can I have him return? - Listen, this is Benjamin Miles Franklin.
我要马上找到曼宏
And I need to speak to Mahone right away.
-富兰克林要找曼宏 -我来接
- It's Franklin for Mahone. - I'll take it.
富兰克林，我是卫勒探员 我们之前没见过面
This is Agent Wheeler. I don't believe we've met before.
我有事要找曼宏
I need to speak to Mahone.
我可以帮你吗？
Something I can help you with?
听着
Listen...
请你传话给他
...I wanna leave a message for him.
你告诉他
You tell him,
告诉他我会照他的要求去做
You tell him that I'll do what he wants me to do, okay?
我只需要多一点时间 我会做的
I just need a little bit more time. I'll do it.
请不要伤害她们
Just don't hurt them.
有听到吗？不要伤害她们
You hear me? Don't hurt them.
什么事？
What's up?
失陪
Excuse me.
（伊利诺州芝加哥 坦斯朵造船厂）
-你疯啦？你来这干嘛？ -小声一点
- Are you crazy? What are you doing here? - Keep your voice down. Keep it down.
你最近好吗？还可以吧？
How you been? You all right?
-很高兴见到你 -我也是，老弟
- It's good to see you, man. - You too, brother.
如果其他人知道你在这 我看他们会很有意见
If the guys knew you were here, they might not be cool about it.
我不会久留，我需要你的帮忙
I ain't hanging around, man. I need a favor.
-你欠我的 -对，你也很清楚
- You owe me. - I do. You know I do.
可是K
Look, it's...
可是你现在的情况 我刚当上父亲，有个小儿子
Look, it's just your situation right now. I mean, I just had a kid, a baby boy...
-我答应犸莉亚K -我不是来惹麻烦的
...and l... I promised Maria... - I didn't come here to cause trouble.
我的朋友不多 我需要你的引介
I'm short on friends. I need you to hook me up.
只有你肯不用预付现金 就愿意做
You're the only one who can do it without the green up front.
我是认真的，拿去，我很需要
I'm serious about this, man. Here. I need it.
好，我试试看
Okay. I'll give it a shot.
-什么时候要？ -越快越好
- By when? - AsAP.
-明天？后天？ -现在
- Tomorrow? The next day? - Now.
现在
Now.
好吧，林克，跟我来
All right, Linc. Come with me.
待命，第六区
Stand by, Marker six,
护卫小队，待命
Escort team, stand by,
待命准备离开
Okay, stand by for exit,
第七区安全
Seven clear,
接近饭店入口
Approaching hotel entrance,
一切看来安全
Everything looks clear,
-他越界了，抓住他 -抓住他K
- He's over the line. Got him. - Take him, Take him down,
-派人制服他 -不准动
- Get some hands on that guy, - Hold it still,
-逮捕他K -把他压在地上
- Detain him, Detain him, - Get him on ground,
质问那家伙
Talk to that guy,
（我们有录音带）
有谁看见他？有媒体吗？
Who saw him go down? Any press?
我们很快就制服他 但有谁看到很难说
We got him down pretty quick but you never know.
-有人可能已经拍到了 -去检查
- Somebody may have gotten a shot. - Check around.
必要时没收照相机
Confiscate cameras if you need to.
在流言传开前，先发表声明
Put out a statement before rumors get started.
还有叫所有人出去
And get everyone out of here.
-快点 -我们还在等进一步的K
- Now. - We're still waiting for the response from...
你我心知肚明 在这种情况下，必须抛开正常程序
You and I both know that this situation requires us to abandon protocol.
我不知道你得怎么呈报 但我要你们的人离开
I don't know what you need to tell them, but I need your men to leave.
立刻
Now.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
你哥在哪里？
Where's your brother?
-我要见总统 -是吗？
- I need to see the president. - Really?
你觉得有可能？
And you think that's a possibility?
-她会想听我要说的话 -我高度怀疑这点
- She'll want to hear what I have to say. - Oh, I highly doubt that.
你唯一能见的人
The only person you get to talk to...
只有我
...is me.
如果你下一个小时还想活命
And the only way you're gonna live through the next hour...
就告诉我你哥在哪里
...is if you tell me where to find your brother.
好
Okay.
-他在安全的地方 -具体一点
- He's in a safe place. - Be more specific.
具体上而言
Specifically...
就是你永远找不到的地方
...a place you will never find him.
我很荣幸
I had the honor...
能够上蒙布克军事学校
...to attend Mountbrook Military Academy...
该校的任务在于
...whose mission it is...
确保本国的伟大精英 未来领导人之崇高
...to ensure the greatness of this country, its future leadership...
鼓励爱国主义
...encouraging patriotism...
扎下强烈道德基础 并提供服务给K
...building a strong moral foundation and providing the service of men...
这些为荣耀 自由和国家效命的人
...committed to the values of honor, freedom and country.
不过，首先K
But, first and foremost...
学校会先教你这招
...they taught you this.
（墨西哥，里约华雷兹）
再教我一次 “樱桃”要怎么说？
How do you say "cherries" again?
看来你要拿更多樱桃来了
Looks like you have to get more cerezas.
宝贝 我替你准备上百颗开心果了
Mami, I got you a hundred pistachios.
-还有刚好的Q量 -我要加在一起吃，两种都要
- With the right amount of salt too. - Well, it's a combination. I need both.
我为何这么听你的？
Why am I sucker for you, huh?
-怎么了？她说什么？ -那人好像茶包
- What? What's she saying? - That looks like T-Bag.
什么？
What?
他说他试图偷机场的行李
He said he was trying to steal luggage from the airport.
他身上有五百万，为何要K？
He's got five million dollars. Why would he...?
除非钱不在他身上
Unless he doesn't have it.
除非钱遗失在机场
Unless he lost it there.
-够了，费南多 -怎么了？
- Stop it, Fernando. - What?
你真的相信那笔钱在机场？
Do you really believe that that money is at the airport?
别管钱了 瞧现在我们拥有的一切
Hey, forget it. Look at what we have together.
你真的要拿来冒险吗？
Do you really wanna risk that?
我们需要的一切都在这里
We have everything that we need.
-除了你的樱桃 -对
- Except your cerezas. - Right.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
费南多
Fernando.
宝贝，我马上回来
Baby. I'll be right back.
你应该知道 我很会认出有毒瘾的人
You gotta know it's not real hard for me to recognize a junkie.
我K的意思是 你看起来不太好
L... l... I'm saying you don't look so good.
我很好
I'm fine.
介意我问你吃什么药吗？
You mind me asking what you're taking?
-拿去，要一颗吗？ -不用
- Here, you want one? - No, that's okay.
留着待会吃
Save it for later.
维拉垂
Varatril.
苯重氮基Q是一种 药效很强的镇定剂
Benzodiazepine's a hard-core tranquilizer, man.
你每天都服用？
Take these every day?
每天20毫克
Twenty milligrams.
你一定感觉像在水中漫步
You must feel like you're walking underwater.
对
I do.
下面非常安静
It's very quiet down here.
那就是你开始服药的原因吧 为了得到安宁？
That's why you started, right? The peace and quiet?
但现在原因都变了，对吧？
That's not why you do it anymore though, is it?
现在是为了治头痛吧？ 你应该是夜不成眠
Now it's the headaches, right? And you probably don't sleep.
你知道这会毁了自己，对吧？
And you know you're gonna destroy yourself, right?
我尚未排除这种可能性
I haven't ruled that out as a possibility.
希望待会你的男友会打电话来
Hope we hear from your boyfriend.
我和曼宏探员有个不同点
There's one difference between me and Agent Mahone.
他不懂一鸟在手的价值 他只会不断旁敲侧击
He doesn't know the value of a bird in the hand. He keeps beating around that bush.
但你若不说出柏劳的下落 我也不在乎
But if you don't give up Burrows, I don't care.
-死一个，剩下一个 -我要和斯科菲尔德先生谈谈
- One down, one to go. - I need to talk to Mr. Scofield.
单独谈
Alone.
总统女士
Madam President.
借一步K
Could I...
谈谈好吗？
...have a word?
这么做不恰当，留您单独和他K
It wouldn't be prudent for me to leave you alone with Mr. Scof...
我的手下就在门外 我有保有隐私的权利
My men are right outside this door. I have a right to privacy.
我担心的K
Your rights...
并非您的权利
...aren't my first concern.
我非得提醒你 现在正跟谁说话吗？
Do I need to remind you who you are talking to?
出去时把门关上
Step outside and close the door behind you.
你为了你哥做的牺牲
The things you do for your brother.
真令人刮目相看
It's impressive.
我想说你也一样
I could say the same for you.
-但我不会说 -记住
- But I won't. - Bear in mind...
你的意见我毫不在乎
...your opinion means little to me.
这段录音
This tape.
在你身上吗？
You have it with you?
没有
No.
但我可以安排让你听听
But I can arrange for you to hear it.
轮不到你替我安排 斯科菲尔德先生
You don't make arrangements for me, Mr. Scofield.
我有专人会去办
I have people for that.
我不太确定录音的内容
I'm not exactly sure what is on this tape...
但我想 对我应该不会有什么用
...but I doubt it's of any interest to me.
那是你和你弟的电话录音
It's a recorded conversation between you and your brother.
我和我弟在他生前 通过数不清的电话K
Well, out of millions of conversations that I had with my brother during his lifetime...
我说具体一点
I'll narrow it down for you.
录音是在他死后录到的
It was recorded sometime after his death.
至于K
And this...
这段录音
...particular conversation...
你可能不会想让外人听到
...you might wanna keep in the family.
东西在哪？
And where is it?
我做了20份备份 放在20个不同的地方
Twenty different copies in 20 different locations.
我现在可以打电话给我哥
I can call my brother right now.
他可以放给你听
He can play it for you.
不能用电话，叫他拿过来
Not on the phone. Have him bring it here.
条件如下
These are the terms.
你用电话听
You can hear it over the phone...
不然就等上新闻再听
...or you can hear it on the news.
你自己决定
It's up to you.
这也是我开始的原因
You know, it's why I started.
开始什么？
Started what?
服药，和你的理由一样
Using. Same reason as you.
为何？ 因为住院实习时整晚不能睡？
Why? Because you had to stay up all night during residency?
因为贝斯手 当着姐妹会的面甩了你？
Because the bass player dumped you in front of the whole sorority?
对，你和我真是同病相怜
Yeah, you and I got a lot in common.
我也见过人死亡
I've seen people die too.
我想你没有害死他们
I'm assuming you didn't make them die.
你需要帮助
You need help.
那不是我要的
Not what I'm looking for.
为了你好 我希望你男友很快会打电话来
For your sake, I hope your boyfriend calls back real soon.
犸丽？
Maricruz?
人都到哪去了？
Where the hell's everybody?
宝贝？
Mami?
瞧瞧你，老朋友苏克
Hey, lookie here. Good old sucre.
你干了什么？ 她们在哪里？犸丽
What'd you do? Where are they? Maricruz.
等等K小声一点
Hey, hey, hey. Keep your cap on.
她们出去替大象宝宝摘苹果了
Out picking apples for the snuffaluffagus.
-要是你敢K -冷静
- Lf you ever... - Calm down.
她们随时会走进来
They're gonna walk back in here any minute.
代表我们有麻烦了
Which means trouble.
除非你想看我试用新枪 在你的拉丁妞身上下手
Unless you wanna see me try out the new T-20-Z on your bella muchacha Mari-poon.
你最好跟我走
I think you better come with me.
什么事？
Yeah?
林克柏劳？
Lincoln Burrows?
卡洛琳雷诺兹
Caroline Reynolds.
听说你有东西要给我听
I understand you have something for me.
-你还在吗？ -我在
- You still there? - Oh, I'm here,
很高兴终于和你通上话
It's good to finally talk to you.
蹲死刑监那242个晚上 我真希望K
Wish I had the chance one of those 242 nights I spent on death row, you...
把录音放出来就是了
Please, just play the tape.
很糟糕，我知道
It's awful, I know,
但别无选择 你必须和一切撇清关系
But the choice was clear, You needed to be far away from all of this,
的确 我是汪汪大海上的戴伦斯岛
I am, I'm the Isle of Terrence, far off to sea,
但还有我帮助你
But I'm still here for you,
听我说，别沉溺在负面想法
Now, listen to me, Don't dwell on the negative,
有些人可以沉溺，卡洛琳
some people deserve to dwell, Caroline.
只要打通电话就能找到我
You know I'm only a phone call away.
你离我也有三千里
And three thousand miles.
你知道这里有多冷吗？
Do you know how cold it is here?
这件事我们讨论过了，戴伦斯
We talked about this, Terrence,
你明知会感到孤单 但只是暂时而已
You knew that you would be lonely, but it's only temporary,
他的起诉程序已经开始了
His appeals process has started already,
这件事会比你的青春 还快过去
This is gonna fly by quicker than your 20s,
世界上的人 很快就会淡忘他
And soon the world will forget all about him,,,
他们也会忘了你，我保证
...and they'll forget about you too. I promise.
可是K
But...
见不到你让我好难熬
...it's killing me not being able to see you...
-亲爱的卡洛琳 -我也很想见你
...sweet Caroline. - I wanna see you too.
-但现在不能这么做 -这栋房子好大
- But that can't happen right now, - This house is so big.
我只能K想着你K
I just... I just think of you...
躺在床上想着你
...lying in bed.
-我知道，我也是 -你的温度、触感
- I know. Me too. - Your warmth, your touch.
他自杀时K
Was it quick...
走得快吗？
...when he killed himself?
比我父亲死时要快很多
Well, it was a lot quicker than how my father died.
他们射中他的背部
They shot him in the back.
他死在我怀里
He died in my arms.
我只想知道他是怎么死的
I just wanna know what happened.
你弟弟向我们道歉
Your brother apologized.
他说完对不起 就把自己轰得脑浆四溢
He said he was sorry and then he blew his brains out all over the wall.
他走得很快
It was quick...
那是他的决定
...and it was his decision.
现在轮你下决定了
And now it's time for you to make yours.
不行K我办不到K
No, no, no, no. Man, you know, l... I can't... I can't do it. I can't do that.
你可以的
Yes, you can.
没什么好怕的
There's nothing to be afraid of.
你还不懂是吗？
You don't get it, do you?
这家伙是阻止不了的
You can't stop this guy.
没有你的合作我阻止不了他 但如果你愿意谈
Not without your cooperation, I can't. But if you talk to me...
如果你告诉我真相，我就能帮助你
...if you tell me what's going on, I can take care of you, okay?
你一定要相信我，富兰克林先生
You've gotta trust me, Mr. Franklin.
我可以帮助你
I can help you.
你是百元钞票吧？
C-Note, right?
对，随便啦
Yeah, whatever.
只要你把曼宏探员的话 一字不差告诉我
All I need you to do is tell me exactly what Agent Mahone told you.
只要你举发曼宏 我会把人生还给你
If you give me Mahone, I'll give you your life back.
上帝在对我微笑，我只能这么说
God's been smiling down on me, I can tell you that.
先是在阿哥马找到疯仔
First I caught up to Haywire up in Algoma.
他在被逮之前 从谷物升降机上跳下
He did a dive off an elevator before they could put him away...
-但我还是能拿赏金 -等等，他死了？
...but I still get the reward. - Wait, wait. He's dead?
对，像撞上卡车玻璃的小虫 希望你别有样学样，苏克
Yep. Like a gnat on a Peterbilt. Hope you don't take the same route, sucre.
-不会，我活着的理由很多 -希望其中包括回福克斯河
- Hell, no. I got plenty reasons to live. - I hope a few of them are in Fox River.
如果你乖乖就范 我或许可以赏犸丽一点钱
Or maybe if you play nice, I'll throw your Maricruz a couple of bills.
-但要先把你抓回去 -你抓我们能拿多少？
- After I turn you in. - How much are you getting for us?
十万 你一定不知道自己值那么多钱吧
A hundred grand. I bet you never thought your ass would be worth all that.
等等K
Wait, wait, wait.
如果我知道哪里有五百万呢？
What if I know where you can get 5 million dollars?
你没听错
You heard me.
-在哪里？ -我可以带你去
- Where is it? - I could take you there...
但你不能把我抓回美国 交给警方
...if you didn't have to take me back to the states and turn me back in.
钱在哪里？
Where is it?
茶包来了
T-Bag's in town.
很久以前我就已下定决心
I made my commitment a long time ago.
我决定把国家摆在自己之上 就像母亲对孩子一般
I agreed to put my country ahead of myself, like a mother does for a child.
我以为K
And I thought...
我的作为是高贵之举 我将得到赏识
...that what I was doing was noble and that I would be rewarded.
你错了
You were wrong.
你还不了解 我也只是个棋子吗？
Don't you see that I'm a pawn in this too?
控制了这个国家的力量
The power that has taken over this country...
就像癌症，而且没有东西能阻止
...is like a cancer and it will stop at nothing.
-我并无权控制 -这件事也一样
- It is out of my control. - So is this.
告诉我你要我怎么做
Tell me what you want from me.
解开我的手铐
Uncuff me.
-我没有钥匙 -你会去拿的
- I don't have the keys. - You'll get them.
第二，我要你安排 让我单独离开
Second, I want you to arrange for me to walk away from here alone.
不准跟踪我
No surveillance.
好
Okay.
最后K
And finally...
我要你用总统赦免权 赦免我和我哥
...I want a presidential pardon for me and my brother...
将我们的罪行一笔勾消
...fully exonerating us of all our crimes.
我要你今天就办好
And I want it today.
我不能随便选一个人赦免
I can't just hand out pardons to anyone I choose.
-有一定的程序和规定 -这次也一样
- There is a process, rules. - This is no exception.
公文会呈报给你批示 就跟其他赦免案一样
A document will be delivered for your approval just like any pardon.
你要签署同意，并交给K
You'll sign it and then file it...
司法部长 他会提交至总统纪录中
...with the attorney general, who'll submit it to Presidential Record.
好吧，你要我签署什么都可以
Fine. I will sign whatever you need me to sign.
你真大方 但你我都清楚这还不够
That's very kind. But we both know that's not enough.
你到底想怎样？
What do you want from me?
我会亲自替你解开手铐 送你出去
I will unlock you myself, walk you out of here.
难道还要我载你去机场？
What, you want me to drive you to the airport?
我只是不像以往那么相信人 尤其是在文件方面
I guess I'm not as trusting as I used to be. Especially with paperwork.
没两下子就遗失了
It's so easy to lose.
我要你出去，到群众面前
Now, I want you to go out there in front of everyone...
在现场转播中 宣布赦免我们的罪
...and announce our full pardon on live TV.
你疯了
You're insane.
事情不是这样办的
That is not the way things are done.
我没有与世隔绝，民众会起疑心
This is not a vacuum. People will ask questions.
立刻上台宣布大赦
Pardon. On stage. Now.
我怎么能确定之后 你不会把录音曝光？
And how do I know that you won't release the tape an hour later?
你无法确定
You don't.
你只能相信我的话
You'll just have to take my word for it.
-我需要更多担保 -你休想拿到
- Well, I need more than that. - Well, you're not gonna get it.
卡洛琳
Caroline...
时候到了
...it's time.
做决定吧
Make your choice.
亚当斯，解开犯人的手铐 把他带来这，释放他
Adams, I need you to uncuff the detainee and bring him here to be released.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我要宣布赦免 斯科菲尔德先生和他的哥哥
I am going to make an announcement pardoning Mr. Scofield and his brother...
他要毫发无伤地离开
...and he will walk away unharmed.
你疯了吗？
Are you out of your mind?
他手头上有明明白白的铁证
He has brought some indisputable evidence to light.
我们现在就能结束一切
We could end this all, right now.
你却让他们离开？
You're gonna let them walk?
我是美国总统 你只是体制下的小卒
I am the commander in chief, and you are a corporate lackey.
决定权在我，你无权过问
I am making the calls now. You have no authority.
我的人会确保
My men will see to it...
斯科菲尔德先生安然离开
...that Mr. Scofield walks away without the interference...
你和你的走狗们不得干涉
...of you and your pit bulls.
-你一个人？ -对
- You alone? - Yeah.
-情况如何？ -三张单程票、一个船舱
- How'd you do? - Three tickets, one cabin, one way.
太好了
Nice.
-我欠你一份 -不，我们扯平了
- I owe you. - No. We're even.
-酒是给你的 -太好了
- These are for you. - Nice.
还有这个
And this.
-这是什么？ -你们越狱时，艾迪
- What's this? - Eddie. When you broke out...
他和我赌一百元 说你会在一周内被抓
...he bet me a hundred bucks you'd be caught in a week.
我说，我认识的林克不可能
I said, no way. Not the Linc I know.
我想应该和你平分
Figured I'd split it with you.
要道别了是吗？
So this is it, huh?
对
Yeah.
祝你好运
Good luck.
-保重 -你也是
- You take care. All right. - You too.
小心一点
You be safe.
-这一带你比较熟 -对，第三街和雷辛街口如何？
- This is your neck of the woods. - Yeah. How's Third and Racine?
我会去等你
I'll be there.
我真的不想这么做，真的
I don't wanna do this. I really don't.
你K在说什么？
What are you talking about?
我已经给你机会了
You can't say that I didn't give you a choice...
你总是爱反抗
...you never take the easy way. You...
我发现你有这个特质
And I noticed that about you. You...
我早该知道你不会屈服 但我有职务在身
I should never expect it to be any different but I have a job to do...
有人逼我要完成职务
...a job that I'm being made to do.
接电话，莎拉
Pick it up, sara.
莎拉，接电话
Sara, pick it up.
-接电话 -等等K
- Pick up. - Wait, wait.
不要动
Don't move.
请你K不要动
Just don't... Don't move.
我要电话，把电话给我
Okay, I need the phone. Give me the phone.
请你留在原地
Stay right where you are, please.
你不会想这么做的
You don't really wanna do this.
我要什么你根本不懂
You don't know the first thing about what I want.
-有收到我的简讯吗？ -有
- You got my message? - Yeah,
-我看到她了 -她正要离开
- I got her. - She's on her way out.
跟踪她 她会带你找到斯科菲尔德
Follow her, She'll take you right to Scofield,
长官
sir...
我们得谈谈
...we need to talk.
几分钟后，总统K
In just a few minutes, the president...
即将要宣布 赦免柏劳和斯科菲尔德
...is going to announce a pardon for Burrows and scofield.
你也清楚 这和目标背道而行
As you're well aware, this is quite a departure.
她一直很合作 但我认为我们该采取行动
She's always been willing to play ball but I think we need to take some action.
长官K
Sir...
我很不想打扰你，但K
...I hate to disturb you...
你可能不了解 她这么做会有什么后果
...but I'm not sure you realize the gravity of what she's about to do.
-迈克 -莎拉
- Michael. - Sara.
-成功了 -大赦？
- It worked. - The pardon?
她马上就要宣布了
She's announcing it any minute.
天啊
Oh, my God.
天啊，迈克，太好了
Oh, my God. Michael, that's amazing.
快来，好吗？
Just get here, okay?
我正在K
I'm on...
高地，湖边的一间仓库
...Highland. It's a warehouse that runs right down to the water.
好，我马上去
Yeah. Yeah, I'm on my way.
-我们成功了 -真的？
- We did it. - Yeah?
你的脸怎么了？
What happened to your face, man?
如果想上车
If you wanna take the ride...
一定得买票
...you gotta buy the ticket.
好吧，德瑞克替我们在货轮上 准备了一个船舱
Yeah, right. Well, Derek hooked us up with a cabin on one of those freighters.
从大湖区到南美洲
South America via the Great Lakes.
已经不需要了 不过很感谢他的啤酒
Well, we're not gonna need that. But this is appreciated.
再说一次，老弟
One more time, bro.
-我们成功了？ -结束了
- We did it? - It's done.
我真希望能见到她的表情
I wish I could've seen the look on her face.
你不会想看的
No, you don't.
我当然想
Oh, yeah, I do.
-不可置信 -她会赦免我们
- Unbelievable. - She's gonna do it.
不可置信
Unbelievable.
总统即将在 卡莱尔大饭店登台演说
The president is now taking the stage here at the Grand carlisle Hotel,
至于演说延后两小时
The 2-hour delay in her appearance,,,
发言人莱恩伯格指出 是因为调查
...due to an investigation characterized by Press secretary Ryan Berg...
一位“过度热诚的民众”所致
...as "an over-zealous fan"...
-你不行这么做 -恐怕我心已决
- You are not going to do this. - I'm afraid I am.
-后果你自己小心 -我已经下定决心了
- Developments you need to be aware of. - I have made my decision...
也希望你不要质疑我的决定
...and I would appreciate you not second-guessing me.
我想你还不了解 我们也知道你的秘密
I don't think you understand. We know your secrets too.
我们也可以轻松让消息曝光
We can reveal them just as easily.
你要扪心自问，谁比较可怕 迈克斯科菲尔德？
You need to ask yourself who you fear more. Michael scofield...
还是我们？
...or us?
-剩30秒 -好
- You've got 30 seconds. - Yeah.
我不耽搁你了
I won't keep you.
-全世界都在等你 -10秒
- The world is waiting. - Ten seconds.
各位先生、女士 欢迎美国总统
Ladies and gentlemen, the President of the United States,
九、八、七、六、五
Nine, eight, seven, six, five...
四、三、二
...four, three, two...
一
感谢各位一整个下午 耐心地等候
Thank you for waiting so patiently all afternoon.
如果不是 有这个美好的州的支持
If it were not for the support of this great state...
我的故乡伊利诺州
...my home state of Illinois...
我今天就不会站在这里
...I would not be here today.
所以我才选择今天
Which is why I have chosen today...
宣布一个非常重要的消息
...to make this very important announcement.
近来有个状况已浮上台面
A situation has recently come to light...
我认为我一定要采取行动
,,, and I feel that I must take action,
身为本国的总统
It is my job as president of this great country,,,
当我接获事实时
,,, to make rational decisions,,,
有责任做出理性决定
,,, when I am given facts,
这决定不只对我最好 也是为了人民的福祉
Decisions that are best not for me but for the people.
因此K
And so...
经过深思熟虑后
...after much consideration...
我很遗憾要向各位宣布
,,, I regret to inform you,,,
我被诊断出 患有高度恶性的癌症
...that I have been diagnosed with a highly malignant form of cancer.
而因为这个理由
And because of that reason,,,
我不再有资格 担任各位的总统
...I am no longer fit to serve as your commander in chief.
为了国家着想，立即生效
In the best interest of this country, effective immediately...
我要卸下美国总统的职位
...I am stepping down as president of the United states.
各位先生女士 总统发布惊人消息
Ladies and gentlemen, in a shocking announcement,,,,
如果她不是总统 录音就毫无用处
If she ain't the president, the tape's useless.
她没有大赦的权利
She can't pardon anyone.
我们落得一头空
We got nothing.
她不再是总统
- She will no longer serve as the president,
我们只剩下一条路可走
There's only one thing we can do.
我们得消失
We gotta disappear.
永远消失
Forever.